MUNAWAR SAUDAGAR

Frontend Developer (React)

Toronto, Canada 🏚 832-704-5648 📞

munawar.saudagar@gmail.com 🖂

Munawar Saudagar in

PROFILE / OBJECTIVE

I am a frontend developer with a good level of backend skills. I have three years of experience in developing responsive frontend applications using React and Bootstrap. I have advanced level expertise in Javascript and CSS. I have good skills in Node, Express, NPM and GIT. I also have some knowledge of Python/ Flask. Previously I developed desktop applications using MS Excel/PowerPoint VBA, Matlab and Fortran.

I am looking for a React-based frontend position that may require some Node-based backend development.

PROJECTS (Click on "↗" for demo)

- React App fetching data from API (<u>7</u>)
- React Calculator (<u>7</u>)
- React-Bootstrap based portfolio (↗)
- Node/Express based REST API
- Python/Flask app (↗)
- Hacker News API based app (↗)

SKILLS

- Javascript (9/10)
- CSS (8/10)
- Bootstrap (6/10)
- Node/Express/NPM/GIT (5/10)
- Communication/Interpersonal (8/10)

- React (7/10)
- HTML5 (8/10)
- Responsive Design (7/10).
- Python/Flask (3/10)
- Quick learner (8/10)

EDUCATION

PhD (Process Control), MS and BE in Chemical Engineering. Got "first position" in BE, "4.0 GPA" in MS and "Best Teaching Assistant" in PhD.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer | Self Employed, Toronto-Canada (10/2019 – Date)

Developed many frontend applications using vanilla Javascript and also based on React. Designed responsive layouts with pure CSS flexbox/grid and also using Bootstrap. Developed some backend applications using Node/Express and Python/Flask

Staff Scientist | SABIC Americas, Houston-USA (11/2014 – 09/2019)

Worked in petrochemical R&D and desktop apps development. Developed a number of VBA/Excel based databases and GUIs.

Section Head / Staff Scientist | SABIC, Riyadh-KSA (10/1997–10/2014)

Involved in development and improvement of chemical technologies and technical software development (with Fortran and VBA).